- [Instructor] Okay, so let's get started on our frontend
by adding Materialize, a CSS library that will provide us
with a great template for our styles,
and then add a main structure for our main page.
And we also want to make sure that we keep
our server running because as we add our new pages,
as we add anything that will speak to the server,
you want to make sure that this is still running.
So, I'm still going to be in the same project here
'cause I'm going to have the backend and the frontend,
but you want to make sure that you run a new server
with a new terminal here.
So, leave this one running.
If you're working in VS Code
or if you're working with your terminal on your computer
make sure you open a brand new window for a new terminal.
I'm going to do this now,
and what I'm going to do is cd into the frontend this time.
So, I'm in the right directory here,
and then I'm going to clear it
and use that as we work on our server.
Okay, so this is our Vite React frontend.
And again, if you haven't initiated a new frontend
with the Vite package go ahead
and go back to that video and create it.
And now what we're going to do is first of all go
into the index.html file
and we're going to add Materialize CSS in here,
so let's go ahead and do that.
So, I'm going to go to the Materialize page,
which is materializecss.com.
And then I'm going to click on Get Started,
and I'm going to use the CDN.
So, I'm going to first copy this link here
for the main CSS and I'm going to go here,
and I'm going to put it just above the title here like so.
And while we're here if you want to change the title
to something else, Soccer application, perfect.
And now what we need is the script to put in the body,
so I'm going to go back here and copy the script like so.
Go back to my project, put it in the body,
so it could be before or after the main.jsx.
I'm going to put it above like so.
And that's all you need to do here.
Now, the next thing I'm going to do is close the HTML
and go in the source folder.
And what I'm going to do is create a folder called Components.
So, go in the source folder, create a new folder,
and call this one Components.
And then inside the Components folder
I'm going to create a new folder,
and I'm going to call this Player.
And we're going to add a few things
in the Player folder down the road.
So, the first one that we're going to add
is PlayerForm.jsx.
So, if you select Player here you can add a new file
that's going to be called PlayerForm.jsx.
Add a new PlayerList.jsx.
And finally, again, add PlayerSingle,
and all of these are going to make sense as we build them.
I'm going to explain them as I build them.
All right, so in the Components folder
I'm going to drag and drop the App.css and the App.jsx,
so now you should have these App.css and App.jsx.
Inside the Components you should have a folder
called Player, which has these three here.
So, run the application very quickly
because we want to make sure that we fix anything
that we broke by moving all of these,
so let's go ahead and do that now.
So, npm start, and you're going to see
probably an error right away.
Actually no, it's not npm start, npm run dev for Vite.
And if you go to localhost:5173
it may actually give you an error.
So, I'm going to open a brand new window, localhost:5173,
and you see there's a few errors.
So, we need to fix those.
So, App.jsx is not in the right folder,
so let's go here and fix that.
So, I'm going to close these here.
And this comes from the index, the main.jsx.
So, it's looking for an App.jsx in the main folder,
but it's actually in the Components.
Let's go and give it where it is exactly.
So, I'm going to do this and then select Components
and then select App.
As I fix this what else it's giving me as an error?
And the viteLogo, which is in the assets.
We're actually not going to use this.
So, let's go into App,
and I'm going to remove those two logo here.
We don't need this,
and I'm going to remove them from the HTML.
And anyways, all of this is going to change fairly quickly.
In fact, if you want to avoid having any issues
you can actually go ahead and delete
all the HTML that we have in this component.
Remove the state, we're not going to use this.
And then just run this, save.
Remove state here, we're not going to use either.
And we should be back to normal here, yep.
And if you go back to the app
it is an empty page, which is normal,
which is what we're looking for.
Okay, so this is it for this video.
Let's move on and keep working on this
in the following videos.